# **Alamgir Munir Qazi**

alamgir@alamgirqazi.com

https://alamgirqazi.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alamgirqazi

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a PhD researcher at the University of Galway, Ireland, working at the intersection of Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Information Retrieval (IR). With 6+ years of industry experience, including as Senior Engineer @ Digitalocean, I bring an engineering perspective to AI research focused on efficiency and practical impact.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## **DevOps**

- Cloud Platforms:
  - Amazon Web Services (AWS): EC2, EKS, Elastic Beanstalk, Route 53, S3, AWS CodePipeline.
  - o Google Cloud Platform (GCP): GKE, Object Store, Cloud Build.
- Orchestration: Kubernetes (K8s/K3s).
- Networking: MetalLB, PowerDNS, dnsdist, KnotDNS, BIND9.
- Automation: Python, Bash.
- Log Management: ELK Stack, Clickhouse.
- CI/CD: Jenkins, AWS CodePipeline. Google Cloud Build.
- Configuration Management & IaC: Ansible.Terraform.
- Messaging System: Apache Kafka, ZeroMQ.

#### Full Stack

- Front-end: Angular, React.js (Next.js).
- Back-end: Node.js, Python, Go.
- Databases: MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Clickhouse, Redis, Postgresql.

## **WORK HISTORY**

## University of Galway

# PhD in Computer Science

2024 - present

- Working at the intersection of Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Information Retrieval (IR).
- My research explores how retrieval-based approaches can outperform large generative models in fact verification.

### DigitalOcean

2023 - 2024

### Senior Engineer, DevOps

- Wrote custom Playbooks in Ansible.
- Setup Jenkins pipelines for CI/CD on AWS EKS.
- Writing IAC using Terraform.
- Python Flask framework. Wrote automated swagger API documentation tool.

#### lotascale.io

2022 - 2023

# **Technical Lead, DevOps**

- As a Team Lead, I play a pivotal role in designing the architecture, system design and development of various cutting-edge products catering to enterprises and telcos.
- Contributed significantly to the solution design and deployment of six major products, demonstrating expertise in handling end-to-end software development processes.
- I helped in migration of the entire VM-based infrastructure to an on-premise Kubernetes environment using K3S

#### **Tech Avenue Pvt Ltd**

2020 - 2022

# Lead Software Engineer (Full Stack / DevOps)

- I played a key role in overseeing a talented team of 9-12 resources and leading by example.
- My responsibilities extended to infrastructure management and DevOps, ensuring seamless deployments.
- Spearheading the DPI Core team, I led the development of packet capture tools (inline & passive) based on libpcap and DPDK, enabling network analysis and monitoring.
- Played a substantial role in successfully delivering three major products, showcasing adeptness in managing end-toend software development processes.

#### Micromerger Pvt. Ltd

2017 - 2020

## Software Engineer (Full-stack / DevOps)

- Oversaw the development of Falaya.com platform. As a team lead, I took on roles as an Angular developer and DevOps expert, successfully establishing a comprehensive pipeline and deploying entire application on AWS.
- Development of a payment gateway application, taking charge of Frontend (Angular) development and deploying the entire infrastructure on Google Cloud using GKE.

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

**International Islamic University** 

Islamabad 2013-2017

**Bachelor of Science** 

Computer Science (BSCS)